Friends, in this video we are going to tell you
how you can download and keep your vehicle's insurance certificate online digitally from home with the help of the Locker application,
as I have downloaded it here.
Now, whenever I need it,
I don't need to carry my original certificate or
any document with me. I can show
my vehicle's insurance certificate to anyone digitally in this way
and its validity will be the same as your
original certificate. Yes
friends, if you also want to download
your insurance certificate online digitally, then stay tuned to
this video
till the end. If you like the video, then
definitely like the video. So
let's start the video. For this,
friends, first of all you have to download
a small secret application from your phone's Google 2,
whose name is Locker. This is
your own application made by the Indian Government,
where you can store any of your
documents online digitally. I will
give you the link of this application in the description of the video, from
where you can directly access it.  You can
download and install the application on your phone.
After the application is downloaded and installed on your phone, the
person in whose name the vehicle is
registered, the person in whose name the
vehicle is registered, should login to this application with his/her Aadhaar number.
I have already done this. So, when
I open it here,
you will see an interface like this. I will tell you
how to download the insurance certificate of your vehicle from here.
For this, you will click on the search bar icon below.
After clicking here,
you will scroll up a little
and here on the category option,
you have to click on a setting called
Transport and
Infrastructure. You can see it here.
Click on Transport and Infrastructure.
After clicking here,
many options will appear in front of you in this manner. So, let
me tell you which option you have to click on.
Here you will see an option called
Ministry of Road Transport and Highways.
You can see Ministry of Road
Transport and Highways. You have to
click on this option. Now, you can do all the work from here.  If
you
want to download your driving license then you will
click on driving license. If you
want to download fitness certificate then you will
click on fitness certificate. You
can download insurance certificate,
vehicle tax receipt, challan,
registration of vehicle. So in this video
we are talking about downloading vehicle insurance
certificate, so we
will click on vehicle insurance certificate. Now
here is a
very easy way to download insurance certificate of your vehicle.
Friends, by default
your name will appear here. Here
you just have to enter the registration number of your vehicle i.e. the
number of your vehicle. You will enter
your father's name, whatever is the
father name or mother name in your Aadhar card, whatever it is.
You will enter it here. You will enter the chassis number of your vehicle.
So let me quickly
enter it here. So friends, here
we have entered the registration number of our vehicle, our
father's name and chassis number. You will get
to see the chassis number in your RC.
I have entered all those things here.
After entering, you will come down and
click on get document.
After clicking on get document  You have to
wait for a few seconds, the online Diesel
Car application will fetch here, you can see that it is
fetching, it takes only a few seconds and
your vehicle insurance certificate will be
downloaded and placed inside your Diesel application,
so let's
wait for a few seconds here, you can see live,
see this is done and it has been saved here, it has been
downloaded, let's scroll
down, here you
can see that the vehicle
insurance certificate has come down and as soon as we
click here, you can see here that it has
opened, where
you can see our registration number, the
policy number is visible here
and the company whose insurance we have taken here,
you can also see it here, so in
this way, wherever
needed, you do
not need to carry the original document with you, in
this way, by opening
your digitally downloaded vehicle insurance
certificate in the Diesel application,
you can show it to any traffic police in
this way and in this
way you  There are many more documents
which you can download online and store them
in your Ler application and also friends, if
you want to download any document from here and
share it with someone, then
click on the three dots here, then here
you get the option to share it, it can be
seen in PDF file, you can
download it, you can delete it, so in
this way with the help of Ler application
you can download and store any of your documents online,
so I hope
you all liked this video,
still if you have any kind of question in your mind,
then
you can ask us by commenting in the comment section below the video, that's all
in this video, will we
meet soon with some new topic in the video, till then
thank you Jai
Hind